# SAMANTHA-RAE **ADAMSON**

### **English and Computer Science Teacher**

High School English and Computer Science teacher committed to helping students learn, grow and embrace opportunities while developing a love for learning. Organized, creative and enthusiastic about teaching and learning. Experienced at teaching culturally diverse student populations while recognizing and addressing individual needs.

### **EXPERIENCE**

January 2017 -July 2017

Fulham Cross Girls' School, London, England

English Teacher, Key Stages 3 - 4

September 2016 – December 2016

Engage Education, London, England Supply Teacher, Key Stages 1 – 4

May 2016 -June 2016

River East School Division, Winnipeg, MB

Substitute Teacher, K – 12

May 2016 -June 2016

Sunrise School Division, Springfield, MB

Substitute Teacher, K – 12

April 2016

September 2015 – Transcona Collegiate Institute, Winnipeg, MB Practicum, English and Computer Science

Grades 9 - 12

September 2014 – **April 2015** 

Miles Macdonald Collegiate Institute,

Winnipeg, MB

Practicum, English and Computer Science

Grades 10 - 12

September 2012 – August 2016

New Directions, Winnipeg, MB

Support Worker for Individuals with Intellectual

Disabilities, ages 12 - 70

## **EDUCATION**

2014 – 2016	Bachelor of Education, University of Manitoba
2009 – 2013	English and Computer Science, Senior Years <b>Bachelor of Arts</b> , University of Manitoba
2009 – 2013	English and Sociology
2005 – 2009	High School Graduate, College Pierre Elliott
	Trudeau
	French Immersion K – 12



204-781-1609 SamyAdamson@gmail.com www.samadamson.com

194 Lynn Lake Drive Winnipeg, MB R2C 4N4



#### **CERTIFICATIONS**

Teachable subjects: English and Computer Science First Aid Non-Violent Crisis Intervention Working Effectively with Violent and Aggressive States

### □ QUALIFICATIONS

Languages: Fluent in English Conversational French

Computing languages: Java, C#, C, Small Basic, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Python

Studied English Literature Studied Sociology with a focus on crime and law Worked with individuals of all ages with intellectual disabilities to create inclusive and supportive environments

#### **REFERENCES**

Bhupesh Malhi, Executive **Education Consultant** bhupesh.malhi@engageeducation.co.uk

Denise Fox, Head of School denisefox@fulhamcollege.net

Laura Grainger, Deputy Headteacher lauragrainger@fulhamcollege.net

Chad Duffield, Computer Science Teacher cduffield@retsd.mb.ca